<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Felix Dollack | Felix</title>
    <link>https://felixdollack.github.io/aboutme/authors/felix-dollack/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://felixdollack.github.io/aboutme/authors/felix-dollack/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Felix Dollack</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 01:24:50 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://felixdollack.github.io/aboutme/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Felix Dollack</title>
      <link>https://felixdollack.github.io/aboutme/authors/felix-dollack/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>El Astrocade 2</title>
      <link>https://felixdollack.github.io/aboutme/project/elastrocade2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 01:24:50 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://felixdollack.github.io/aboutme/project/elastrocade2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The original version of &lt;a href=&#34;../elastrocade/&#34;&gt;El Astrocade&lt;/a&gt; was limited due to hardware
necessities. For better portability El Astrocade 2 was an attempt to minify the
original game while keeping most of the control aspects the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An aluminum frame box with a acrylic display used to project the game from below
was created. The final length of each side of the table was too short to make
players walk. Therefore, we opted for balance control using WiiFit balance boards.
Shifting weight to the left or right side controlled the movement of the spaceship.
Leaning backward on the balance board triggered the shield for defense against damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The balance board has a weight limit, so we had to rethink the jump action to
trigger shooting. We decided to build very soft buttons to trigger a shot.
The buttons sense touch by infrared light refraction measured with custom PCB boards
on the inside. Every touch was reflected with a light animation inside the button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;ars.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work was exhibited during the 5-day lasting &lt;a href=&#34;https://ars.electronica.art/outofthebox/en/&#34;&gt;Ars Electronica Festival 2019&lt;/a&gt;
in Linz, Austria. It was well received and a magnet for approximately 1000
visitors a day. The total down-time during the exhibition was less than 5 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source code might be released on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.github.com/felixdollack&#34;&gt;www.github.com/felixdollack&lt;/a&gt; at a later point
after cleaning it a little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project status: finished.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El Astrocade</title>
      <link>https://felixdollack.github.io/aboutme/project/elastrocade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://felixdollack.github.io/aboutme/project/elastrocade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We, the authors, proposed a shooting game based on whole body motion as part of a
student project. Over the course of 12 months we ran through multiple iterations
of designing the appearance and interactions within the game. The core elements
of the finalized version are motion tracking and a helmet with haptic and visual
feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First iteration of the game projection:
&lt;img src=&#34;first_iteration.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The helmet (picture below) is used to present haptic feedback when the spaceships
receive damage through lasers or by collision with asteroids. When the ship gets
hit a LED strip below the visor flashes red. The rest of the time the LED strip
fades from green to red to indicate the life points of the spaceship. A display
at the front of the helmet shows the team color. Motion tracking markers on top
of the hemet (not in the picture) are used to track the position of the players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;head.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The body position (x,y,z) of 2 teams with 2 players each is measured to give
shared control over a spaceship to each team. One player of each team controls
the X and Y direction of the ship. The players height controls the ships actions.
At the beginning of each game the height of the players is picked up. The ship
can shoot a laser when either of the team members jumps or activate a shield for
defense when one player of the team squats during the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;birdview.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game is entirely written in C++ with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openframeworks.cc&#34;&gt;openFrameworks&lt;/a&gt;
and was developed for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://intron.kz.tsukuba.ac.jp/archives/788&#34;&gt;Large Space&lt;/a&gt;
at the University of Tsukuba. The game graphics are projected on a 5 by 5 meter
floor area and players move along the sides of the projection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;final.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This final system increases physical activity of all players thanks to the body
motion control and fosters teamwork through shared control of the spaceship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source code might be released on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.github.com/felixdollack&#34;&gt;www.github.com/felixdollack&lt;/a&gt; at a later point
after cleaning it a little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project status: finished.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
